Guide to the Joseph Bruchac Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- September 1998 Acquisition, 1969-1998; 13.62 linear feet (15 boxes)
  - Writings
    - Writings of Others
      - Einhorn, Lois J. The Native American Oral Tradition, 1998 (Box 90)
      - Jones, Blackwolf and Gina Jones
        Related Archival Materials note
        See: Blackwolf and Gina Jones
      - Limón, Graciela: Song of the Hummingbird (Henry Holt Publishing), undated (Box 90)
      - McLemore, Regina, 1997 (Box 90)
      - Perry, Robert. Life With the Little People, 1993 (Box 90)
      - Red-Eagle, Philip H. Red Earth, final draft, 1997 (Box 90)
      - Sings-Alone, Duncan, undated (Box 90)
      - Susag, Dottie, 1995-1996; 2 (Box 90)
      - Susag, Dottie. Roots and Branches, 1997 (Box 90)
      - Wilson, Darryl. In the Shadow of the Old House, 1997 (Box 90)
      - Tale Trader, 1996 May (Box 90)
      - Buried Roots and Indestructible Seeds, undated (Box 90)
  - Subject Files
    - University of Arizona: correspondence and statement, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Returning of the Gift: Arizona reviews, 1994 (Box 91)
    - ASAIL: correspondence, 1996 (Box 91)
    - August House Publishers Inc.: correspondence, 1996 (Box 91)
    - Barbed Wire, Barbed Tongues; correspondence; project in progress on Native American prison literature, 1995-1997 (Box 91)
    - BOCES listing, 1996 (Box 91)
    - Boyd Mills Press: Writers in the Kitchen cookbook with Bruchac contribution and correspondence, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Breakfast Serials (newspaper series): correspondence and sample (by AVI), 1997-1998 (Box 91)
    - Many Nations: unbound galley, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Many Nations: reviews, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Many Nations: correspondence, 1997 (Box 91)
    - British Museum Press: correspondence, 1998 (Box 91)
    - Brook/Bauman: correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 91)
    - Broken Rainbow: screenplay and associated materials, 1996 (Box 91)
    - Cabuto, Michael: correspondence, 1996-1998; 2 (Box 91)
    - The Snapping Turtle: draft and Candlewick Press correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 91)
    - Candlewick Press, 1998 (Box 91)
    - CMCL: correspondence, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Chenoo: correspondence, 1998 (Box 91)
    - Chenoo: novel manuscript, 1998; 2 (Box 91)
    - Chenoo: complete rewrite, 1998 (Box 91)
    - Children's Literature connection: correspondence, 1996, 1998 (Box 91)
    - Cinco Puntos Press: correspondence, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Civil Rights Journal: Bruchac contribution, manuscript, and correspondence, 1997 (Box 91)
    - The Companion Magazine: Bruchac writing Contemporary Poets: correspondence, 1998 (Box 91)
    - Listing of contemporary storytellers and correspondence, 1995 (Box 91)
    - The Continuum Publishing Group: correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 91)
    - The Council Press: flyers, 1995 (Box 91)
    - Coyote Brothers: play and correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 91)
    - Cross Cultural Communications: flyer, 1993 (Box 91)
    - Crossing Press: correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 91)
    - Dawn Land/Long River: summaries, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Deep Ecology of the Masculine Spirit: correspondence, 1996 (Box 91)
    - Defenders of wildlife: magazine and correspondence, 1998 (Box 91)
    - Denver Museum Press: correspondence, 1998 (Box 91)
    - Dover Books Anthology: correspondence, 1995 (Box 91)
    - Earthlight, undated (Box 91)
    - Environmental Stories (Scotland): correspondence, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Essays and articles, 1992 (Box 91)
    - Earth Visions-Old Forge: correspondence, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Clarissa Pinkola Estes, 1994 (Box 91)
    - Families Learning Together: correspondence, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Flags of Native Peoples of U.S.: correspondence and information, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Forkroads: reviews and writing by Bruchac, 1996 (Box 91)
    - Foxy: novel, 1993 (Box 91)
    - Fulcrum Publishing: correspondence and unidentified, 1994-1997 (Box 91)
    - Fulcrum Publishing: correspondence statements, 1997 (Box 91)
    - Fulcrum Publishing: correspondence referring to "Native American Games & Stories", 1997-1998 (Box 91)
    - Fulcrum Publishing: royalties, 1996 (Box 91)
    - Fulcrum Publishing: correspondence, 1996 (Box 91)
    - Roots of Survival: reviews, 1996 (Box 91)
    - Keepers of the Earth: newspaper clippings, 1991 (Box 91)
    - Keepers of the Earth: royalties, 1991 (Box 91)
    - Glencoe/McGraw Hill: correspondence, 1997 (Box 91)
    - The Good Red Coat Magazine: correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 91)
    - Green Mountain College: correspondence, 1998 (Box 91)
    - Green Mountain College: correspondence and catalog, 1996-1997 (Box 91)
    - Greenwood Publishing: "Encyclopedia of Animal Rights," correspondence, 1995 (Box 91)
    - George Bird Grinnell American Indian Children's Fund, 1998 (Box 91)
    - Gluskabe and the Four Wishes: unbound galleys, 1995 (Box 91)
    - Harcourt, 1998 (Box 92)
    - Harcourt: Look Into the Sky, 1998 (Box 92)
    - Harcourt: unidentified, 1996-1997 (Box 92)
    - Harcourt: Squanto's Journey, 1997 (Box 92)
    - Harcourt Brace: poetry book, 1998 (Box 92)
    - Harcourt: Author biography, 1997 (Box 92)
    - [Harcourt]: Tell Me a Tale, 1997 (Box 92)
    - Harcourt: Tell Me a Tale, final galleys, 1996 December (Box 92)
    - Tell Me a Tale: permissions, 1996 (Box 92)
    - YiYi the Spider Story, 1996 (Box 92)
    - Tell Me a Tale: rough pages, 1996 (Box 92)
    - Lasting Echoes: reviews, 1998 (Box 92)
    - Lasting Echoes: cover and illustrations, 1977 (Box 92)
    - Seven Generations/ Lasting Echoes: corrected first draft, 1997 July 2 (Box 92)
    - Lasting Echoes: master pages, 1997 (Box 92)
    - Lasting Echoes (7 Generations): final draft, 1997 (Box 92)
    - Permission requests for Lasting Echoes, 1997 (Box 92)
    - Lasting Echoes: rough pages, 1997; 2 (Box 92)
    - Lasting Echoes: manuscript, 1997 (Box 92)
    - Lasting Echoes: cover, undated (Box 92)
    - Lasting Echoes: early drafts, 1998, undated (Box 93)
    - Home: A Journey Through America, by Thomas Locker, 1997 (Box 93)
    - Reviews: Between Earth and Sky, 1997 (Box 93)
    - Between Earth and Sky: songs, undated (Box 93)
    - Between Earth and Sky: Locker poster idea, undated (Box 93)
    - Sacagawea, 1996 (Box 93)
    - Harcourt catalogs, 1998 (Box 93)
    - Harcourt: school visits list, 1996 (Box 93)
    - New England University Press: The Waters Between, 1998 (Box 93)
    - New England University Press (Hardscrabble Books): Waters Between, 1997 (Box 93)
    - The Waters Between, undated; 3 (Box 93)
    - Hauprich photographs. Jesse, Jim, and Joe Bruchac, 1996 (Box 93)
    - Good Mind Records. Bill Greenfield Stories, 1998 (Box 93)
    - Holt, Rhinehart. Myth and Folklore, 1996 (Box 93)
    - Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston. YiYi, 1996 December (Box 93)
    - Holy Cow! Press. No Borders, 1998 (Box 93)
    - Holy Cow! Press. Turtle Meat contract, 1992 (Box 93)
    - Holy Cow Press. No Borders, 1997 (Box 93)
    - Holy Cow! Press, 1995 (Box 93)
    - Houghton Mifflin, 1995 (Box 93)
    - Instructor's Magazine (Writer's Workshop), 1997 (Box 93)
    - Interview, by Susan Gardner, 1995-1996 (Box 93)
    - Interview, Connie Zitlow, 1997 March (Box 93)
    - In the Spirit of Turtle Island. Native American film, 1994 (Box 93)
    - In Their Own Words: Guidelines for Using Traditional Native American Stories, 1996 (Box 93)
    - Invocations for a New Millennium, 1998 (Box 93)
    - Barabara Kouts, 1995-1997; 4 (Box 93)
    - Libraries Unlimited. World Folklore Series, 1996-1997 (Box 94)
    - Legends from the Four Winds, 1996 (Box 94)
    - Ligature, 1994 (Box 94)
    - Meg Lippert, undated (Box 94)
    - Listening Library (See's Behind Trees), 1998 (Box 94)
    - Listening Library, undated (Box 94)
    - Lee & Low Books, 1995-1998 (Box 94)
    - Bridgewater: Crazy Horse's Vision, 1996, undated (Box 94)
    - Ken Lopez, Bookseller, 1996 (Box 94)
    - Ken Lopez. Archive, 1998 (Box 94)
    - MacArthur Foundation, 1996 (Box 94)
    - McDougal Littell. The Language of Literature. Internet McClanahan/ McMillan, 1991 (Box 94)
    - University of Michigan Press, 1998 (Box 94)
    - NAPT, 1997 (Box 94)
    - Naropa Institute, 1995-1996 (Box 94)
    - National Book Foundation, 1996-1997 (Box 94)
    - Native American Public Television. Wolves. Revision ideas, 1997 November 28 (Box 94)
    - Native American Public Television. Screenplay project, 1996 (Box 94)
    - National Storytelling Association publications, 1995 (Box 94)
    - Native American Touchstones, 1993 (Box 94)
    - Native American Public Television. Wolves. 4th draft, 1998 April (Box 94)
    - Native American Public Television. Wolves. Revised, 1997 November 29 (Box 94)
    - Native American Public Television. Wolves, 1997, undated; 2 (Box 94)
    - NSA Delphi Study, 1997 (Box 94)
    - NAPT Film Project, 1997 (Box 94)
    - University of Nebraska, 1997 (Box 94)
    - New England University Press (Hardscrabble Books): correspondence, 1998 (Box 94)
    - New Hampshire Historical Society. Storytelling tape, 1995 (Box 94)
    - New Jersey Outdoors, 1997 (Box 94)
    - New Radio and Performing Arts. National Parks Report Proposal. Regine and Helen, 1997 (Box 94)
    - Oprah Winfrey/ABA Breakfast, 1993 (Box 94)
    - University of Oklahoma, 1997 (Box 94)
    - The Other Book of Virtues, 1996 (Box 94)
    - Out of the Past: proposal, 1997 (Box 94)
    - Richard C. Owen Publishers, 1996 (Box 94)
    - Oyate, 1998 (Box 94)
    - Paintbrush. Monograph issue, 1997 (Box 94)
    - Parabola. "Miracles" issue, 1997 (Box 94)
    - Parabola, 1998 (Box 94)
    - Ely Parker documentary. WXXI, 1996-1997 (Box 94)
    - Paths to Well Being Project, 1996 (Box 94)
    - People's Poetry Gathering, Poets House/City Lore, 1997 (Box 94)
    - Permission requests, 1994 (Box 94)
    - Phati'tude, 1997 (Box 94)
    - Philomel: Paper Star, 1997 (Box 95)
    - Philomel (Michael Green), 1996 (Box 95)
    - Poetry International, 1997 (Box 95)
    - Planned Television Arts. Sandy Trupp, 1997 (Box 95)
    - Pruett Publishing, 1998 (Box 95)
    - Publication Rights Clearinghouse, 1996 (Box 95)
    - Publisher's Weekly, 1996 (Box 95)
    - Puffin Books (Moki), 1996 (Box 95)
    - Pushing Up the Sky. Philosophy anthology, 1996 (Box 95)
    - Putnam, 1998 (Box 95)
    - Putnam Philomel, 1995 (Box 95)
    - The Earth Under Sky Bear's Feet. Trumpet Book Club, 1996 (Box 95)
    - Putnam and Grosset Philomel, 1997 (Box 95)
    - Putnam and Grosset Group, 1996 (Box 95)
    - Quarasan Press, 1995 (Box 95)
    - Random House. Trail of Tears, 1996-1998; 3 (Box 95)
    - Random House. Shana Corey letters re Trail of Tears, 1998 (Box 95)
    - Red Crane: The Dance House, by Joseph Marshall, undated (Box 95)
    - Rhino Records, 1997 (Box 95)
    - Roberts Rinehart. One Spirit, Many Peoples, 1997 (Box 95)
    - Roberts Rinehart. Steve Garvan, 1996 (Box 95)
    - Rodale Press. Storytelling program, 1997 (Box 95)
    - Sail, 1997 (Box 95)
    - Salmon Run Press, 1994 (Box 95)
    - Sasquatch Books (Linda Stark), 1997 (Box 95)
    - Scholastic Network, 1996-1998; 2 (Box 95)
    - Slovak stories, 1969, undated (Box 95)
    - The Soul Unearthed. Anthology, 1996 (Box 95)
    - Speak, 1997 (Box 95)
    - Storm Belt (France), 1994 (Box 95)
    - Storytelling Magazine, 1995-1997; 2 (Box 95)
    - Storytelling TV: Stacy Goforth (Loretta Lynn), 1997 (Box 95)
    - Syracuse University Press, 1995 (Box 95)
    - Thoughtful Books. "When I Think About My Father", 1995 (Box 96)
    - Through Indian Eyes, 1998 (Box 96)
    - Ticknor and Fields, 1993 (Box 96)
    - Troll Educational Catalog, undated (Box 96)
    - Turtle Island TV Show. Sandy Web, 1994 (Box 96)
    - Two Beavers Production, 1993-1994 (Box 96)
    - Voice of Native Authors in Children's Literature, 1997-1998 (Box 96)
    - Anna Vojtech. Plants book, 1989-1991 (Box 96)
    - Amerinda/Talking Stick, 1998 (Box 96)
    - Voyagers (Storyteller series proposal), 1996 (Box 96)
    - WAMC "Rachel's Place", 1996 (Box 96)
    - When the Chenno Howls. File draft, copyedited, 1998 (Box 96)
    - When the Chenno Howls. Galleys, 1998 January (Box 96)
    - When the Chenno Howls. Reviews, undated (Box 96)
    - When the Chenno Howls. Manuscript, undated (Box 96)
    - Walker and Company. Monster Stories, 1997 (Box 96)
    - Walker & Co., 1996-1998; 2 (Box 96)
    - Weston Woods Studio. "Giving Thanks", 1997 (Box 96)
    - Whelks Walk Press, 1998 (Box 96)
    - When I Was Your Age, 1997 (Box 96)
    - Windigo Books. Ross/Woods, 1996 (Box 96)
    - The Coyote Brothers. Play, 1995; 2 (Box 96)
    - Other Subject Files
      - [Wyandot Run Elementary School], 1997 (Box 96)
      - Roots of Survival. Book tour, 1996 Fall (Box 96)
      - [Borders], 1996 November-December (Box 96)
      - Matela, Montana, 1996 October (Box 96)
      - Fall, 1996 (Box 97)
      - NCTE. Chicago, 1996 November (Box 97)
      - San Antonio Book Fair, 1996 November (Box 97)
      - September/October, 1996 (Box 97)
      - Roots of Survival, Minneapolis/St. Paul, 1996 (Box 97)
      - Roots of Survival, West Coast Tour, 1996 (Box 97)
      - National Storytelling Festival, 1996 (Box 97)
      - Oklahoma Festival of Books, 1996 October (Box 97)
      - Boston/Three Apples, 1996 (Box 97)
      - June-August, 1996 (Box 97)
      - ALA. New York, 1996 (Box 97)
      - March-April, 1996 (Box 97)
      - Wichita, Kansas, 1996 May 13-16 (Box 97)
      - IRA, 1996 (Box 97)
      - May-June, 1996 (Box 97)
      - Booking Inquiries, 1996 (Box 97)
      - January-February, 1996 (Box 97)
      - Bookings, 1996 (Box 97)
      - Unidentified, 1996 (Box 98)
      - Children's Literature, 1996 (Box 98)
      - Power of Story, 1996 (Box 98)
      - Itinerary, 1993 (Box 98)
  - Computer media
    - P. Willis BRBL, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0001; 1 (Box 99)
    - WP 4.2 Jan. 87, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0002; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0003; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0004; 1 (Box 99)
    - Excat Let Msc, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0005; 1 (Box 99)
    - Msc, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0006; 1 (Box 99)
    - NEH V1 V2, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0007; 1 (Box 99)
    - V2, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0008; 1 (Box 99)
    - v2 (*.fin), 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0009; 1 (Box 99)
    - v2 (*.fin) (*.dol), 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0010; 1 (Box 99)
    - v2 *.fin, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0011; 1 (Box 99)
    - v2 .fin .ind .sha hugh, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0012; 1 (Box 99)
    - Arm Bib Excat, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0013; 1 (Box 99)
    - msc, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0014; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC FOXY: Novel 1, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0015; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC NO TELEPHONE TO HEAVEN: novel 2, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0016; 1 (Box 99)
    - TALL TALES 1, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0017; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC: GOING HOME: short stories 3, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0018; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC SURVIVAL THIS WAY PART II: interview 4, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0019; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC THE DAWN LAND novel 5, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0020; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC POETRY: 1983-1989 6, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0021; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC GATHERING THE BONES essays 7, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0022; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC BREAKS a novel 8, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0023; 1 (Box 99)
    - Format 17 Feb 86 Misc BA Shailor, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0024; 1 (Box 99)
    - FORMAT 20 March 86 Allback 2.4, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0025; 1 (Box 99)
    - FORMAT 20 March 86 Allback 2.5, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0026; 1 (Box 99)
    - FORMAT 20 March 86, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0027; 1 (Box 99)
    - No. 1 Aug. 30. 1983 BACK UP HARD DISC Aug. 30. 1983, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0028; 1 (Box 99)
    - F 1DAWN ch.1-16, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0029; 1 (Box 99)
    - F 2DAWN Ch. 17-37, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0030; 1 (Box 99)
    - F BACKUP 9985 JESSE 1, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0031; 1 (Box 99)
    - F BACKUP 9985 2, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0032; 1 (Box 99)
    - F BACKUP 9985 3 12/84, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0033; 1 (Box 99)
    - Eagle Computer 96 TPI v.2.30 SPELLBINDER with C & D DRIVE PATCH D/S 6/06/83, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0034; 1 (Box 99)
    - Eagle Computer CPM 80 CLDIR UTILITY D/S 10/83, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0035; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0036; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0037; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0038; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0039; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0040; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0041; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0042; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0043; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0044; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0045; 1 (Box 99)
    - F, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0046; 1 (Box 99)
    - F, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0047; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0048; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0049; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0050; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0051; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0052; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0053; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0054; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0055; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0056; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0057; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0058; 1 (Box 99)
    - NATIVE GAMES AND STORIES, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0059; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0060; 1 (Box 99)
    - TRAIL OF TEARS, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0061; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOE BRUCHAC for Archive Writings 1996-1998 Microsoft Word 4.0 Mac, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0062; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC Archive 1998 #2 Candlewick, Random House, Chenoo 98 rewrite Microsoft Word 4.0 Macintosh, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0063; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC Archive 98 #3 Bridgewater Walker Microsoft Word 4.0 Macintosh, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0064; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC ARCHIVE 98 #4 Wolves acrenplay 2,3,4, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0065; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC ARCHIVE 98 #5 Wolves original Screenplay, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0066; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC ARCHIVE #6 Dial (1 0f 2), 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0067; 1 (Box 99)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC ARCHIVE #7 Dial (2 of 2), 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0068; 1 (Box 99)
    - THE COYOTE BROTHERS, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0069; 1 (Box 99)
    - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0070; 1 (Box 99)
    - SEVEN GENERATIONS Final Draft, 1998-ycal-0922-ak-0071; 1 (Box 99)
- February 1999 Acquisition, 1979-1998; 4.46 linear feet (5 boxes) + 1 roll
  Contains unarranged subject files, most concerning storytelling performances.
  - Subject Files
    - Student essays, art, and thank you letters, 1997; 15 (Box 100)
    - Thank you letters, undated; 2 (Box 101 (Roll))
    - Scarf with a bulldog pin, undated (Box 102)
    - Thank you letter from Carthage Middle School, 1997 October (Box 102)
    - Honorary Ph.D from Wheelock College, 1996 May (Box 102)
    - Other papers and correspondence, 1979-1992; 36 (Box 103)
    - Other papers and correspondence, undated; 11 (Box 104)
    - National Geographic, 1981-1992; 15 (Box 104)
    - National Geographic, 1981-1992; 10 (Box 105)
    - Photograph album from Madison Station, 1998 March 24 (Box 105)
    - Storytelling. Printed material, undated; 3 (Box 105)
- April 1999 Acquisition, 1977-1998; 10 linear feet (10 boxes)
  Organized into two subseries of Subject Files, each arranged roughly alphabetically.
  Contains materials relating to Bruchac's writings and appearances; other Native American writers; Returning the Gift Native American writers conferences, 1990s; and the Wordcraft Circle of Native Writers & Storytellers, 1990s, including audiocassettes and videocassettes.
  - Subject Files
    - Accountant, 1989 (Box 106)
    - Advisory Council, 1991 (Box 106)
    - American Indian Institute at the University of Oklahoma, 1990 (Box 106)
    - Arctic to Amazonia Alliance, 1991 (Box 106)
    - Artist With Class, 1991 (Box 106)
    - AT & T Foundation, undated (Box 106)
    - ATLATL, 1988-1990 (Box 106)
    - Attendees: Returning the Gift, 1992 (Box 106)
    - Balance Sheet, 1991-1992 (Box 106)
    - Bamboo Ridge, 1991 (Box 106)
    - Barriero, Jose, 1991-1992 (Box 106)
    - Bay Foundation: report, 1991 (Box 106)
    - Bay Foundation, 1990-1993 (Box 106)
    - Beyond Survival, 1993 (Box 106)
    - Book fair/book exhibits, 1992 (Box 106)
    - Book list: multiple copies, 1990-1993 (Box 106)
    - Budgets, 1991-1992 (Box 106)
    - Bynner, Witter Foundation, 1991-1993 (Box 106)
    - Calhoun, Jeanetta. Resume, undated (Box 106)
    - Canadian Writers, 1992 (Box 106)
    - Canyon Records and other tape suppliers, 1986-1988 (Box 106)
    - Catalogs NADP, 1989 (Box 106)
    - Childrens Book Press, 1989 (Box 106)
    - Conference participants, undated (Box 106)
    - Costner, Kevin, 1991 (Box 106)
    - Craige, Karen, 1991-1992 (Box 106)
    - Crosswind, 1991 (Box 106)
    - Cultural survival, 1991 (Box 106)
    - Cummings Foundation, 1990-1991 (Box 106)
    - Curbstone Press, 1991 (Box 106)
    - A Day in the Life of Native America, 1991 (Box 106)
    - Deep Dish TV, 1992 (Box 106)
    - Directory of Native Writers, undated (Box 106)
    - Dodge Foundation, 1990-1992 (Box 106)
    - Donors: individual, 1993 (Box 106)
    - Draft program, undated (Box 106)
    - Draft of directory, undated (Box 106)
    - Dungannon Foundation, 1991 (Box 106)
    - The Earth Circle Foundation. Will Channing, 1991-1992 (Box 106)
    - The Educational Foundation, 1992-1993 (Box 106)
    - Endorsements: Returning the Gift, 1988-1991 (Box 106)
    - Encounters, 1992 (Box 106)
    - En' Owkin Centre. Jeannette Armstrong, 1991 (Box 106)
    - Evaluations, 1992 (Box 106)
    - Expenses incurred, 1990 (Box 106)
    - Exxon, 1991 (Box 106)
    - Fadden, John. Illustration/logo, undated (Box 107)
    - Fiction award, 1992 (Box 107)
    - Film of festival, 1992 (Box 107)
    - Financial records: Oklahoma Office, 1991-1992 (Box 107)
    - Financial: tax-exempt 990 forms, 1983-1990 (Box 107)
    - First Book Awards, 1991-1998 (Box 107)
    - First People Gathering, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Fiscal information for grant applications, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Foreign scholars and translators, 1991 (Box 107)
    - The Four Directions, 1992 (Box 107)
    - Foundations: list, 1990 (Box 107)
    - Gannett Foundation, 1984-1991 (Box 107)
    - Garza, Jose, 1990-1991 (Box 107)
    - Geigomah, Hanay, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Grant Applications: Returning the Gift, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Grant support, undated (Box 107)
    - Grants: press release, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Hearst Foundation, 1992 (Box 107)
    - Hitachi Foundation, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Hobson, Barbara, 1990-1993 (Box 107)
    - Hobson, Geary, 1991-1992 (Box 107)
    - Hunter Mountain, 1982-1988 (Box 107)
    - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1990 (Box 107)
    - Indian Youth of America, 1991 (Box 107)
    - The Indigemous Eye/Tiwg, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Indigenous thought, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Individual sponsors, 1991-1992 (Box 107)
    - Information requests, 1991 (Box 107)
    - INIPA (Information Network of Indigenous Peoples), 1990 (Box 107)
    - Institute of Alaska Native Arts, 1992 (Box 107)
    - Institute of American Indian Arts, 1992 (Box 107)
    - Invitation questionnaire, undated (Box 107)
    - Island Press, 1991 (Box 107)
    - The Johnson Foundation, 1990-91 (Box 107)
    - Kahionhes, John Fadden, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Kellogg Foundation, 1991-1992 (Box 107)
    - Kress, Francesca, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Laila, 1990 (Box 107)
    - Lannan Foundation, 1992 (Box 107)
    - Letters of support, 1991 (Box 107)
    - Livingston, Kip, 1991 (Box 107)
    - McDonald, Peter, 1990-1993 (Box 107)
    - MacArthur Foundation, 1991-1992 (Box 107)